<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Axelay (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Axelay</name>
		<desc>This planet was once a quiet, peaceful place to live, until...they came...

An unknown alien race came to this planet and promptly laid waste to it. The remaining defense force has been sent out to try and defeat them. One lucky person gets to fly the latest line of defense ships made: the AX-77 Axelay. However, these ships are still in the prototype stage, and as such, only one exists.

So get out there and head to the alien's homeworld. With some luck, you may just be able to take them out at the source...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Axelay (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19920901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Battletoads-Double Dragon (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Battletoads &amp; Double Dragon</name>
		<desc>Earth is under fire by Colossus, a battleship the size of a city. Using powerful laser cannons, it has destroyed most of Earth's defence forces, while its many troops clean up the rest of the planet. All expect for 5 warriors.

The Battletoads, who are well aware of evil forces in the galaxy, join forces with Billy and Jimmy Lee from Double Dragon to defend Earth from the deadly ship and its troops. Using a range of special moves you must fight your way through the streets into the heart of the ship and destroy it.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Battletoads-Double Dragon (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19931001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Rareware</developer>
		<publisher>Tradewest</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Battletoads in Battlemaniacs (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Battletoads in Battlemaniacs</name>
		<desc>The three battletoads Zitz, Rash and Pimple are in Tibet to witness the presentation of the Psicone Gamescape, a virtual reality machine. All of a sudden a monster jumps out of the gameworld, captures both the Psicone CEO's daughter &amp; Zitz and takes them back into the Gamescape. Of course Rash and Pimple will have to enter the Gamescape and rescue them.

Battletoads in Battlemaniacs is another game in the Battletoads series by Rare. Much like its predecessor, it blends fighting game elements (in the style of Double Dragon) with other kinds of gameplay, like racing levels, "snake riding" levels and such. There are some bonus levels between some of the regular ones, where the player can collect extra lives.

Buddies can team up and defeat the opposition together in the two coop-modes available. In mode A, players can hit each other while in mode B, they can't.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Battletoads in Battlemaniacs (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19930602T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Rareware</developer>
		<publisher>Tradewest</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Aladdin (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Aladdin</name>
		<desc>For years, Jafar, the Sultan's evil advisor has sought a magic treasure - a single lamp that holds the key to the greatest power in the world. With this goal in sight, Jafar learns that only one person in the world can claim the magic lamp from the dreaded Cave of Wonders - one whose rags hide a heart that is pure - a diamond in the rough!
Join Aladdin and his pet monkey Abu, as they race through the marketplace toward their date with destiny. Watch as Jafar tricks our hero and his friend into retrieving the lamp from the dangerous Cave of Wonders. But Aladding and Abu outwit Jafar, releading the power of a wacky blue Genie! Aladding will have the chance to spoil Jafar's devious plans and win the hand of the beautiful princess Jasmine. But it will take more than magic to make his wishes come true...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Aladdin (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19931102T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Donkey Kong Country 2 - Diddy's Kong Quest (USA) (En,Fr) (Rev 1).zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Country 2 : Diddy's Kong Quest</name>
		<desc>Donkey Kong has been kong-napped by the nasty K.Rool and the Kremlings, and it is up to Diddy Kong and his girl-friend Dixie Kong to save him.

All the familiar enemies and helpful friends return, along with some new characters, including the wise Wrinkly Kong who will teach you some important lessons in gameplay. Again the emphasis is on banana collecting, where as every 100 bananas makes one extra life. Apart from beating K. Rool and rescuing Donkey Kong, there are extra missions that can be completed. Collect enough K. Rool Krem Coins to open up the routes to the Lost World, while every level has a hidden Hero Coin to collect.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Donkey Kong Country 2 - Diddy's Kong Quest (USA) (En,Fr) (Rev 1)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19951205T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Rareware</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Donkey Kong Country 3 - Dixie Kong's Double Trouble! (USA) (En,Fr).zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Country 3 : Dixie Kong's Double Trouble!</name>
		<desc>This time both Donkey Kong and Diddy Kong have been kong-napped by a mysterious new leader of the Kremlings, and it's up to Dixie and new team mate Kiddy Kong to save the day.

New elements to the series includes the Brother Bears, thirteen Bears who, if you pay them with Bear Coins found in each level, will aid you in your quest by building certain items. Also, new bonus mission have you playing a 1st/3rd person shooter style party game. Plus a host of new enemies, the usual huge end of world bosses and a collection of the Kong family who will help you out as best they can.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Donkey Kong Country 3 - Dixie Kong's Double Trouble! (USA) (En,Fr)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19961122T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Rareware</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Platform / Run Jump</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Double Dragon V - The Shadow Falls (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Double Dragon V : The Shadow Falls</name>
		<desc>Double Dragon returns, this time as a VS. fighter, in the same mold as Street Fighter. Based on the Double Dragon animated series, which is loosely based on the original arcade game, Jimmy and Billy and a host of other characters fight it out in a tournament fighter. 

The Shadow Master, who has created a deadly virus which he plans to destroy the world with, is waiting for you at the end of the path to victory. You'll have to fight your way through many evil characters before you face the Shadow Master. Beat him, and the world is saved for another day.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Double Dragon V - The Shadow Falls (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19940701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Leland Interactive Media</developer>
		<publisher>Tradewest</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./F-Zero (USA).zip</path>
		<name>F-Zero</name>
		<desc>F-Zero is a futuristic racing game, set in the year 2560. The player chooses one of the four available hovercars and then can race with other hovercars in one of the gameplay modes - "Practice" or "Grand Prix". 

In "Practice" mode, the player chooses one track where he competes with one other hovercar to win the race (or there can be no rival at all, if you so wish). In "Grand Prix", the player must complete a series of races with several competitors. Each race consists of five laps. 

The hovercar has a limited Power meter, which represents the machine's health and decreases when the hovercar collides with the track boundaries and other players. If power runs out, the hovercar explodes and the player loses the race. There are repair areas near the start line, which restore power to the player's hovercar if he drives into them. The tracks contain many more or less dangerous traps, such as icefields or landmines. 

Completing a lap awards the player a "Super Jet" which can be activated at any time to give a short speed boost. The hovercar can keep up to three Super Jets and use them when necessary. 

Completing a lap also gives points, which give the player a life when enough are accumulated. The player can lose a life in the Grand Prix mode if his hovercar explodes, if his hovercar somehow falls out of the track or if he ends up too far behind the other racers.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/F-Zero (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19901121T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Race 3rd Pers. view</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gradius III (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Gradius III</name>
		<desc>Gradius III is the third game in Konami's long-running space shooter series, which also includes Life Force and Nemesis. As with most Gradius titles, you control the highly advanced Vic Viper space fighter against hordes of foes. Weapons can be selected from pre-arranged loadouts or you can create your own custom loadout. The game can be played by a single player, or by two players in alternating turns. The game offers three levels of difficulty.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Gradius III (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19901221T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./GunForce (USA).zip</path>
		<name>GunForce : Battle Fire Engulfed Terror Island</name>
		<desc>The player takes control of a soldier who is dropped off onto an island and must fight his way through hordes of enemy soldiers until he gets to the final showdown in order to protect Mother Earth from the invaders.

Gameplay consists of moving forward and blasting all the enemies who get in the way. The player starts out with a normal gun, but can find other weapons throughout a level, such as a flamethrower or a laser gun. While the normal gun has an infinite amount of bullets, the other types of weapons will eventually run out of ammo. With these weapons, the player can shoot either straight, up, or on a diagonal. The player will also have the opportunity to commandeer a vehicle, which they can also fire bullets from.

The player starts with 5 lives and 3 continues. Each of the stages must be defeated in a certain amount of time or the player loses one of those lives.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/GunForce (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19921101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Bits Studios</developer>
		<publisher>Irem</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Illusion of Gaia (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Illusion of Gaia</name>
		<desc>Will is a young boy whose father disappeared long time ago. Now Will lives in a small town with his grandparents. He possesses unusual abilities of pushing and pulling things without touching them. One day, he finds in his house a girl, who soon turns out to be the princess Kara. Kara's father, king Edward, wants her to marry a mysterious person called the Jackal. Kara asks Will to help her to escape the palace, and soon they both get involved in a string of mystery and conspiracies...

The game is somewhat similar to the famous Legend of Zelda games, also having a "save the princess" story, and employing real-time combat. Will can also use his special abilities to solve simple environmental puzzles.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Illusion of Gaia (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19940901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Quintet</developer>
		<publisher>Enix</publisher>
		<genre>Role playing games</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kirby Super Star (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Kirby Super Star</name>
		<desc>"Kirby Super Star" is another platformer in the Kirby series, distinguished for having an unusually versatile character, who can fly and gain the abilities of his foes.

The game is actually a set of seven main games: Spring Breeze, Dynablade, Gourmet Race, The Great Cave Offensive are unlocked at first, and later Metaknight's Revenge, Milky Way Wishes and The Arena become available, as well as a couple of minor minigames.

These are all typical Kirby platformers, each one with its own set of levels and different gameplay. In most of them you can consume monsters and learn their special abilities, but in Milky Way Wishes abilities are instead collected in a manner similar to Metroid. Offensive Cave features levels with various obstacles, hidden treasures and some elementary lever-pulling kind of puzzle solving. Metaknight's Revenge is the only game on the cartridge with a (fairly strict) timer.  The Arena is a "boss rush" mode, asking players to defeat every boss in the game with limited health refills and on one life.

Kirby Super Star is best known for its two-player cooperative play option, which has given it a reputation as a party game.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Kirby Super Star (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19960920T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>HAL Laboratory</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kirby's Avalanche (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Kirby's Avalanche</name>
		<desc>The First Annual Dream Land's Avalanche Competition is about to get under way, and as Kirby and a host of characters from the Kirby series, you can join the tournament and become Avalanche king.

Avalanche is similar to Puyo Puyo, and has you stacking colored blobs similar in a way to Tetris. When a certain amount of one color is stacked, an explosion occurs and the screen clears of those blobs, which then appear in the other players screen (either the CPU or a second player). When your screen is cleared before the other player, you move onto the next round, and so on until the final boss. The winner of that match is then crowned the Avalanche king.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Kirby's Avalanche (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19950201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>HAL Laboratory</developer>
		<publisher>Banpresto</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kirby's Ghost Trap (Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Kirby's Avalanche</name>
		<desc>The First Annual Dream Land's Avalanche Competition is about to get under way, and as Kirby and a host of characters from the Kirby series, you can join the tournament and become Avalanche king.

Avalanche is similar to Puyo Puyo, and has you stacking colored blobs similar in a way to Tetris. When a certain amount of one color is stacked, an explosion occurs and the screen clears of those blobs, which then appear in the other players screen (either the CPU or a second player). When your screen is cleared before the other player, you move onto the next round, and so on until the final boss. The winner of that match is then crowned the Avalanche king.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Kirby's Ghost Trap (Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19950201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>HAL Laboratory</developer>
		<publisher>Banpresto</publisher>
		<genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
		<players>2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kirby's Dream Course (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Kirby's Dream Course</name>
		<desc>Kirby's Dream Course is an innovative SNES game featuring everyone's favourite pink blob, Kirby. After his adventures in Dream Land we find him in this mini golf game where Kirby himself is the ball, and you must guide him around each hole using the sort of bar system that you see in most golf games. Where this game differs, however, is in the fact that you need to eliminate all on-screen enemies before you can guide Kirby into the hole and complete it. As per usual in golf games, the more strokes it takes you to complete the whole, the lower your score - so make sure you aim Kirby just right!

You'll find eight courses and a total of sixty-four holes in the game, not including the final showdown with King Dedede, as well as an action-packed two-player mode.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Kirby's Dream Course (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19950201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>HAL Laboratory</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Sports / Golf</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Kirby's Dream Land 3 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Kirby's Dream Land 3</name>
		<desc>That mean old King Dedede is at it again! He's causing his mischief and Dreamland's in trouble! Kirby, the resident hero of Dreamland, sets out to teach Dedede a lesson, this time with the help of many of his good friends!

But wait! Something's wrong! Dedede doesn't seem to be himself...

Looks like Kirby has to stop Dedede and find out what is wrong with him! It almost seems like something's controlling him...
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Kirby's Dream Land 3 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19971127T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>HAL Laboratory</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mega Man 7 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Mega Man 7</name>
		<desc>At long last, Mega Man had finally manage to beat the evil Dr. Wily! With this defeat, Wily was thrown in jail, seemingly for good. The world would no longer be subject to his madness.

But remember, Dr. Wily is mad, but he's not stupid. He had a backup plan...and all he had to do was just wait...

6 months had passed, and somewhere from deep within Wily's abandoned lab, 4 hidden capsules activated and opened. His backup plan was in action...he had hidden 4 new Wily Robots that would spring him out of jail so he could continue his mad reign.

When Mega Man hears the word that Wily was busting out of prison, he rushes onto the scene, only to encounter a strange robot he had never seen before named Bass. Bass tells Mega Man to back off, that he would stop Wily, and that Mega Man was no longer needed.

Think that's gonna stop Mega Man? No way! Mega Man takes off to put a stop to Dr. Wily and find out exactly whose side Bass is on...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Mega Man 7 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19950902T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mega Man X2 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Mega Man X2</name>
		<desc>Sigma, the leader of the Maverick army, was destroyed when he underestimated his opponent: a lone warrior, awakened into a time he never knew...X.

6 months had passed, and X rose to the rank of leader of the Maverick Hunters. His first task was to eliminate the last of the Mavericks. But as he began his assignment, a mysterious group of Reploids calling themselves the X-Hunters appeared with a message to X: the remains of his fallen comrade, Zero, were in the hands of the X-Hunters, and they planned on resurrecting Zero to fight alongside them and for their fallen leader, Sigma.

X must now stop the X-Hunters and rescue Zero, and once again prevent Sigma from rising back into ultimate power.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Mega Man X2 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19950303T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Metal Combat - Falcon's Revenge (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Metal Combat : Falcon's Revenge</name>
		<desc>Following the events of Battle Clash, the Battle Game Chiefs had been defeated. But the world did not return to peace and instead new Chiefs and new machines rose up to rule the world. Like before, the Chiefs use giant robots known as Standing Tanks (STs). Seeing the world in trouble, the hero pilots who had defeated the Battle Chiefs decide to once again enter the Battle Game using an improved version of their ST, the Falcon. The truth behind the Battle Game will take the Falcon deep into space...

Metal Combat: Falcon's Revenge is a first person shooter designed for the Super Scope Light Gun. Gameplay is identical to Battle Clash. The player takes the role of the gunner of the giant robot, movement is handled automatically by the game, scrolling the screen. Players must keep the enemy robot in the gunsights and blast away at different parts of it, while also intercepting enemy missiles and counter-attacks. All robots have a weak point that will increase the damage done to them. Power-ups such as Neutron Beams and Plasma Bombs can be picked up following the completion of certain stages, and equipped at the beginning of combat.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Metal Combat - Falcon's Revenge (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19931201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Intelligent Systems</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Lightgun Shooter</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mickey Mania - The Timeless Adventures of Mickey Mouse (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Mickey Mania : The Timeless Adventures of Mickey Mouse</name>
		<desc>Mickey Mouse gets a chance to go down memory lane and walk through the timeless adventures he has lived. Mickey Mania is a platformer where all the levels are based on Mickey's most famous cartoons. The levels range about 75 years, starting off with "Steamboat Willie" and going all the way to "The Prince and the Pauper".

The gameplay consists mostly of jumping and marble throwing at enemies, with an occasional puzzle element.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Mickey Mania - The Timeless Adventures of Mickey Mouse (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19941001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Travellers Tales</developer>
		<publisher>Sony Imagesoft</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mickey's Playtown Adventure - A Day of Discovery! (USA) (Proto).zip</path>
		<name>Mickey's Playtown Adventure : A Day of Discovery!</name>
		<desc>The game stars Mickey Mouse as he goes on an adventure in Toontown to solve puzzles and riddles involving letters, numbers, shapes and objects. The game was canceled before it could be released, despite being finished.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Mickey's Playtown Adventure - A Day of Discovery! (USA) (Proto)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<developer>Visual Concepts</developer>
		<publisher>HiTech Software</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mickey's Ultimate Challenge (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Mickey's Ultimate Challenge</name>
		<desc>One night, as Mickey (or Minnie) lay in bed reading a book of fairy tales, he started to wonder how it would be to live in a far off land, in a magic castle. As he fell asleep, he woke up in the Kingdom of Beanwick, which is constantly tormented by earthquakes. Then, he offers his help to solve the mystery behind those earthquakes.

Mickey's Ultimate Challenge is a puzzle game in which the player chooses either Mickey or Minnie to play with. They'll find five characters from the Disney's universe in the kingdom, and will be prompted to help them in several tasks.

Each task is a different puzzle, given by a specific character. Daisy, for instance, will ask help to clean the castle's paintings hanging on a wall. The task is in fact a memory game, where Mickey or Minnie must clean the pictures matching pairs. After completing one task, they'll receive a gift.

After completing all tasks, Mickey or Minnie must trade the gifts they won with the right characters. For instance, after finishing Goofy's task, they will receive his hammer. The player must then guess who among the other characters would like to receive that hammer.

Giving the right items to the right characters will allow Mickey or Minnie access to the last puzzle and character.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Mickey's Ultimate Challenge (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19940202T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Master Designer Software</developer>
		<publisher>HiTech Software</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mega Man X3 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Mega Man X3</name>
		<desc>A Reploid scientist named Dr. Doppler begins creation of a new city for Reploids, which will bring a new era of peace to the Reploids and humans. But something goes terribly wrong, and now Mavericks have begun to appear everywhere! It's up to X and Zero to find out who is behind this Maverick revolt and bring them down for good!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Mega Man X3 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19960214T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Aleste (Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Space Megaforce</name>
		<desc>Compile's Aleste series lands on the SNES with the appropriately named Super Aleste. Taking the role of a lone starfighter pilot, you are tasked with destroying an evil alien armada in standard 2D shooter fashion. And while you may be alone, you certainly won't be underpowered, with eight different types of weapons, each having six power-up levels for a grand total of 48 firing modes (not counting bomb power-ups) Super Aleste boasts one of the largest arsenals in 2D shooter history.

Gameplay is single-player only with 3 difficulty levels. Also included is a short campaign with different levels that plays mostly like a "survival" mode with the objective being to outlast the time limit and rack the most points.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Aleste (Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19920428T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Compile</developer>
		<publisher>Toho</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Street Fighter II (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Street Fighter II</name>
		<desc>The original Street Fighter II is a famous fighting game. Players select from one of eight characters: Ryu, Ken, Blanka, E. Honda, Zangief, Chun Li, Guile and Dhalsim to do battle with. They must then use their combat strengths to defeat the other seven fighters followed by four boss characters: M. Bison, Vega, Sagat and Balrog. Each character represents a certain country and has their own reasons for wanting to win against the others.

Each character contains his own selection of basic fighting techniques based on three styles of punches and three styles of kicks. The effect of each of these changes depending on the characters orientation (ducking, airborne or standing still). Street Fighter 2 made famous the "button combination" style of gameplay used to unleash powerful moves specific to each character. These include the ability to project fireballs, channel electricity or capture the opponent in a tight suplex.

Street Fighter 2 is one of the most cloned fighting games and its effects on gameplay and fighting games specifically can not be understated. Street Fighter 2 is responsible for making popular several different elements.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Street Fighter II (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19920610T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Street Fighter II Turbo (USA) (Rev 1).zip</path>
		<name>Street Fighter II Turbo</name>
		<desc>Choose from twelve street fighters from around the world, skilled in a variety of martial arts -- for instance, a character named E.Honda is a sumo wrestler from Japan, while Ken is a master of Tae Kwon Do from the United States. Journey to different countries to defeat other fighters, eventually leading up to a battle with evil man M.Bison. Besides the standard punches and kicks, each character can also execute special moves, such as energy projectiles or lightning-fast kicks, for more damage or to create a chain of hit combos. 

This home version is a re-release of the original Street Fighter 2 game with several major improvements: the 'boss' characters (Vega, Balrog, Sagat, and M. Bison) are automatically unlocked for you to play, each character receives some new or upgraded moves and costume colors, and you can select a Turbo speed level which lets you play at a faster speed. It is based on the arcade re-release by the same name which also contained the subtitle "Hyper Fighting."
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Street Fighter II Turbo (USA) (Rev 1)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19930801T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Donkey Kong Country (USA) (Rev 2).zip</path>
		<name>Donkey Kong Country</name>
		<desc>King K. Rool has stolen Donkey Kong's banana stash, and Donkey Kong needs your help to get them back. In search of K. Rool, the Kremling horde impedes your progress. Kremlings, crocodile-like creatures, include Kritters (they succumb to a simple jump on the head), Krushas (they are virtually indestructible), and others. There are also other enemies that block your path, such as beavers, snakes, vultures. Leading them are dastardly bosses, including Very Gnawty, Necky, Bumble B, and Dumb Drum, and they all bar the way with their own special blend of villainy.

Donkey Kong is joined by Diddy Kong: these two primates differ significantly. For example, Donkey Kong is generally stronger; he can destroy most enemies with a single jump and can lift barrels straight over his head to throw them farther. On the other hand, Diddy is faster and not as strong as Donkey; he can run really fast and do cartwheels. Diddy carries barrels in front of him, creating a shield against frontal attacks.

The game is split into different worlds, which are split into different levels. Each level contains bonus areas, where one can collect bananas, medallions, and lives. At the end of each world is a boss, which is usually a larger version of a minor enemy.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Donkey Kong Country (USA) (Rev 2)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19941125T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Rareware</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Double Dragon (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super Double Dragon</name>
		<desc>Billy and Jimmy Lee return for another adventure. This time, fellow martial arts instructor and narcotics investigator, Marian, has disappeared while attempting to infiltrate the ruthless criminal mob known as the Black Shadow Warriors.

Once again it is up to you (and a friend) to battle your way through a selection of side-scrolling beat 'em up levels to defeat the Shadow Warriors and their leader Duke, and save Marian.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Double Dragon (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19921001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Tecmo</developer>
		<publisher>Tradewest</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Ghouls'n Ghosts (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super Ghouls'n Ghosts</name>
		<desc>4 years after Arthur saved Princess PrinPrin from the evil demon Loki, a wonderful celebration is about to take place! Arthur and the Princess are engaged, and the wedding is to take place at last! Thousands from around the kingdom have come to witness this joyous event!

But somewhere in the darkness of the forest lurks a horrible evil...

Arthur and PrinPrin are spending a quiet moment locked in embrace, when she is suddenly snatched away by a huge demon! As her screams echo through the night, Arthur rushes from the castle, and pursues the demon to the graveyard, where he is greeted by hundreds of horrible ghouls and monsters!

Now, this time, they've gone too far...Arthur is ready for them...
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Ghouls'n Ghosts (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19911101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Mario World (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super Mario World</name>
		<desc>Once again, the evil Bowser has captured Princess Peach (while on a holiday on Yoshi's Island), and it's up to Mario to save her. To aid him in his quest, Mario must use the flying ability of the feather to get him to places hard to reach. But what's even more important is his new friend, the dinosaur Yoshi, who Mario can ride through each level and eat the enemies.

Over 90 levels are on offer, with plenty of Bowser's evil koopas and new characters around each level. Apart from saving Peach, you can also save some of Yoshi's friends, other dinosaurs that each have a special attack. Each level also contains a set of extra items to collect, including dinosaur coins, and break the tape at the end of each level to collect stars, that allow you to open up the bonus games.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Mario World (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19910813T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Mario World 2 - Yoshi's Island (USA) (Rev 1).zip</path>
		<name>Super Mario World 2 : Yoshi's Island</name>
		<desc>The events of Yoshi's Island take place in the past. Mario was one of two twin brothers whom the evil Magikoopa Kamek tried to kidnap. Kamek kidnapped one of the brothers, but the second, Mario, fell down on Yoshi's island, where Yoshis live. The Yoshis decided to carry baby Mario and to bring him to his parents. But Kamek has sent troops and hordes of monsters to stop the Yoshis and to kidnap Mario.

In the game, players control the differently colored Yoshis most of the time. Mario is a helpless baby unless a star that makes him invincible is collected. As a Yoshi, players can swallow enemies to make eggs; these eggs are used for attacking other enemies and activating switches. Yoshi can do a flutter jump to clear large gaps that a regular jump can't. Players can also pound the ground for attacks and also flipping certain switches. Additionally, Yoshis can transform into vehicles, such as a helicopter, submarine, or a train. If Mario is dismounted from a Yoshi, a countdown will start, and Yoshi must catch the baby before Kamek's servants kidnap it. When Mario is invincible, he doesn't ride on Yoshi and is immune to attack. While invincible, Mario can run up certain walls.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Mario World 2 - Yoshi's Island (USA) (Rev 1)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19951004T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Metroid (Japan, USA) (En,Ja).zip</path>
		<name>Super Metroid</name>
		<desc>Join forces with the power of Samus for a Super Metroid clash!
Take on the legion of space pirates and take on a new Metroid force as you progress through the underworld of the planet Zebes! It's up to you and Samus to find the larval Metroid before evil forces misuse its energy.
Every vicious corner, every hidden passageway on the planet Zebes holds menacing creatures ready for battle... including the horrible Ridley and the giant lizard, Kraid. Use your lethal somersault to make enemies bite the dust. Use an electric beam through the gaps. No one will stop you or Samus. But beware! It seems that Mother Brain is back...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Metroid (Japan, USA) (En,Ja)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19940418T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Adventure</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Turrican (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super Turrican</name>
		<desc>Super Turrican is the next generation installment of the famous Turrican Series. Once again it is up to the U.S.S. Freedom Forces to get into their Turrican Assault Suits and drive back the forces of "The Machine".

Similar to it's predecessors, Super Turican features large levels that are crammed with secrets and can be explored freely and in any direction. To get rid of the numerous enemies, Turrican can use three upgradeable shots: A spreadshot, a powerful laser and a rebound that bounces off of walls. Additionally, there is a Freeze-Beam that can be used to temporarily freeze enemies. It is fully rotatable, and therefor also a great help in discovering secret capsules. These capsules contain powerups and can often be used to reach secret areas. Last but not least, Turrican has the ability to transform into an energy wheel (as long as he has enough special energy), which enables him to lay mines and even makes him invincible.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Turrican (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Factor 5</developer>
		<publisher>Hudson</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Turrican 2 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super Turrican 2</name>
		<desc>Super Turrican is back, and once again the USS Freedom Forces have to prevent the evil Machine from harming innocent civilizations. 
This requires the player to jump and shoot his way through large levels filled with lots of enemies. To get rid of all the enemies, several different weapons can be used, most of which are already familiar to players from previous installments of the series: a Laser, a Spread-shot, and a(improved) Rebound. There is also the option to go
into "wheel-mode" for a limited time to become invincible, lay mines and shoot rockets. The Flamethrower is new to the series as well as the Rope, which can be used to climb walls, cling to platforms or pick up out-of-reach items. Much like in side-scrolling shooters, you can now pick up homing missiles as secondary weapons. The biggest difference to previous Turrican-games however, is the fact that in Super Turrican 2 almost half of the levels are strictly linear and don't feature any large secret areas that have become somewhat of a trademark of the series.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Turrican 2 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19951102T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Ocean</developer>
		<publisher>Ocean</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Valis IV (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super Valis IV</name>
		<desc>Once upon a time, there was a prince named Gallagher. He was entrusted with a magical ring that granted him great powers. But he was too weak to control the power of the ring, and became possessed by it. The mad prince was sealed into a crystal, but many years later managed to break out, planning to wreak havoc on the Dream World and to conquer it! Yuko, the heroine of the three previous Valis games, is no longer a sacred Valis warrior - she has become a goddess. Lena, a young girl who wants to become a Valis warrior, is the new main character, who must prove to Yuko she is worthy to wield the sword of Valis, that will eventually stop the evil plans of Gallagher.

Like the previous games in the series, this is an action platform game. You can fight enemies with melee weapons or use magic. In order to cast magic spells, you must gather special items while fighting off regular enemies. At the end of a level, a boss enemy battle awaits you. The game features cut scenes with animé-style graphics to advance the story.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Valis IV (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19930201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Telenet</developer>
		<publisher>Atlus</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Great Circus Mystery Starring Mickey &amp; Minnie, The (USA).zip</path>
		<name>The Great Circus Mystery Starring Mickey &amp; Minnie</name>
		<desc>Starring Mickey and Minnie Mouse, the two plan to spend the day at the Circus only to find that it's deserted. Believing that someone is responsible, you must dress up in different outfits such as Safari and Western, as you try to find clues to solve the mystery behind the disappereance of the performers, including your pals Donald Duck and Pluto.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Great Circus Mystery Starring Mickey &amp; Minnie, The (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19941001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Legend of Zelda, The - A Link to the Past (USA).zip</path>
		<name>The Legend of Zelda : A Link to the Past</name>
		<desc>Venture back to Hyrule and an age of magic and heroes. The predecessors of Link and Zelda face monsters on the march when a menacing magician takes over the kingdom. Only you can prevent his evil plot from shattering the land of Hyrule. In your quest, you'll venture into twisting mazes, dungeons, palaces and shadowy forests. Test your mettle with mighty swords and magical weapons. Or heft a boulder and hurl it at your enemies. If the going gets tough, dive into a river - you can swim to escape! Learn the powerful spells, locate magical artifacts and solve the mysteries of the evil magician and the hidden realm of Hyrule.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Legend of Zelda, The - A Link to the Past (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19920413T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Nintendo</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./U.N. Squadron (USA).zip</path>
		<name>U.N. Squadron</name>
		<desc>Side-scrolling shoot-em-up, in a similar style to such games as Gradius, R-Type and Scramble. The aim is to wipe out the enemy, which has gathered around the allied airspace of 'Area 88', in a series of military aircraft-based scenarios.
 You choose one of three unique pilots; Shin Kazama, Micky Schymon or Greg Gates, each with varying abilities at damage repair, weapon handling and flying skill, and engage the enemy over a series of challenging missions. The player starts out with the weakest plane, the F8E Crusader, which can only be armed with a very basic range weapons. But, through completing various missions, enough cash can be raised to purchase higher-quality aircraft. These superior planes are more agile, have improved resilience to damage and have a greater range of fire. Furthermore, the more advanced fighters can be armed with superior special weapons, such as napalm.
 The missions include attacks on sand bases, the nuclear submarine 'Seavet' and enemy supply camps, as well as seeing off groups of airborne 'bandits' who swarm-in on Area 88.
 The enemy is plentiful, and the pace is frantic. Shoot at everything on the screen that moves, and the allied forces might just come out on top......</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/U.N. Squadron (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19910901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Castlevania - Dracula X (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Castlevania : Dracula X</name>
		<desc>In Transylvania, people lived in fear of the evil Count Dracula. The ultimate embodiment of evil, Dracula swept his dark hand over the land, making the people mere sheep for his thirst for blood. But when a young woman named Sonia Belmont came forth to confront him, he made a horrible mistake: he underestimated her. Thus, the battle between Dracula and the Belmont family began.

Now, in the late 18th century, the battle still rages on...

Dracula has been resurrected by a cult of black magic to cast his shadow of fear and terror over the land once again. But now, Dracula takes his fight to those the Belmonts are close to. He kidnaps two girls, Annette and Maria Renard, to bring forth the latest Belmont, so that he may destroy the bloodline for good.

Richter Belmont, Annette's lover, has no choice now, but to take up the legendary Vampire Killer and follow his destiny: to battle Dracula and save Annette and Maria.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Castlevania - Dracula X (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19950901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./R-Type III (USA).zip</path>
		<name>R-Type III</name>
		<desc>UNDER A NEW BYDO THREAT, EARTH RETALIATES It was believed on Earth that the deadly BYDO Empire had been destroyed--but now they've returned, as nasty as ever. Their ships and armies are more powerful than before, and Earth will surely be conquered unless the new R-90 ship can destroy them. Powered with engines that launch it into different dimensions, and armed with the Round, Shadow, and Cyclone Forces, R-90 has what it takes to wipe out the BYDO threat. Then, the BYDO mother ship must be found and destroyed to entirely erase the species from our galaxy.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/R-Type III (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19941001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Jaleco</developer>
		<publisher>Irem</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Castlevania IV (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super Castlevania IV</name>
		<desc>Simon Belmont returns in the first Castlevania title to grace the SNES.  The console may be different, but the setup is very familiar: The place is Transylvania.  The villain is Count Dracula.

Belmont has the classic Castlevania assortment of weapons (the famous whip, daggers, axes, fire bombs, boomerangs) at his disposal, and he gains strength and points by collecting various-sized hearts, coin purses, and pork chops. 

Like most Castlevania games, Super Castlevania IV is a 2D side-scrolling action game. However, it is 2D with more depth than ever before. Parallax scrolling and rotating chambers are some of the "Mode 7" effects made possible by the SNES hardware.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super Castlevania IV (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19911031T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super R-Type (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Super R-Type</name>
		<desc>A Galactic Battle Begins! The BYDO Empire of mutant extra-terrestrials is back with evil intent and awesome power. You'll feel the heat of their attack as never before with the extra powerful graphics and unbelievable realism of the Super NES. Now the evil Empire is poised to launch a new attack on Earth. Only the revolutionary R-9 stands between these monsters and doom.

Are they invincible? You'll need lightning reflexes, intuitive moves and a big dose of cosmic luck to hold your own! "R" you ready? The mutants "R" ready for you!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/snes/Super R-Type (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19910901T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Irem</developer>
		<publisher>Nintendo</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
	</game>
</gameList>
