<?xml version="1.0"?>
<gameList>
	<game>
		<path>./Aladdin (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Aladdin</name>
		<desc>The game from Virgin based on the 1992 animated Disney film is a side-scrolling platformer.

The player controls Aladdin, who must make his way through several levels based on locations from the movie: from the streets and rooftops of Agrabah, the Cave of Wonders and the Sultan's dungeon to the final confrontation in Grand Vizier Jafar's palace. The Sultan's guards and also animals of the desert want to hinder Aladdin in his way. He can defend himself with his sword or by throwing apples. Next to apples, Aladdin can also collect gems which can be traded for lives and continues with a traveling trader. Finding Genie or Abu icons enables bonus rounds. The Genie bonus round is a game of luck played for apples, gems or extra lives. In Abu's bonus round, the player controls the little monkey who has to catch bonus items that fall from the sky, but without touching any of the unwanted objects like rocks and pots.

The game's humorous animations were created by Walt Disney Feature Animation.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Aladdin (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19931111T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Virgin</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Aladdin II (Taiwan) (En) (Unl).zip</path>
		<name>Aladdin 2</name>
		<desc>Aladdin II is an unlicensed Mega Drive port of the SNES version of Disney's Aladdin, originally made by Capcom in 1994.
It was developed by an unknown company and was likely published by X Boy.
This port can be considered the "opposite" of Aladdin 2000, a port of Virgin's Aladdin to the SNES.
Some of Aladdin's moves as well as some of the enemy sprites can be found in Hercules 2, which was published by X Boy in 1999.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Aladdin II (Taiwan) (En) (Unl)-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<publisher>Homebrew</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Alex Kidd in the Enchanted Castle (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Alex Kidd in the Enchanted Castle</name>
		<desc>Alex Kidd, resident of planet Aries, is the brother to the king. One day he comes across a rumor that his long lost father, King Thor, is alive and somewhere on the planet Paperock. 

Now Paperock is a place where you have to be good at the game of 'Paper, Rock and Scissors' to get anywhere. With that knowledge you must take control of Alex, guide him through the odd natured, unfriendly planet and help him find his father.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Alex Kidd in the Enchanted Castle (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.55</rating>
		<releasedate>19890814T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Alisia Dragoon (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Alisia Dragoon</name>
		<desc>The pace is intense. Enemies come at Alisia from everywhere. And nowhere. Battle hordes of crazed barbarians, mow down mobs of poisonous centipedes, and slay squadrons of winged gargoyles. Blast enemies in waves or one by one with multi-directional, auto-targeting laser fire.

Recruit killer companions like the DragonFrye, Ball O'Fire, Thunder Raven and Boomerang Lizard. Use them to hurl blistering boomerangs, fireballs, and electrical attacks. With Alisia's super-tough fighting skills, fry enemies to a crisp. And prove once and for all that you can go hand-to-hand with evil and come out the champion!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Alisia Dragoon (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19920201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Game Arts</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Altered Beast (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Altered Beast</name>
		<desc>In this coin-op conversion, you are a hero raised from the dead by the god Zeus to rescue his daughter Athena. With a scenery inspired by Ancient Greece, you have to fight hordes of undead and demons, with a boss at the end of each level until you meet the god Neff, who holds the girl captive.

The title refers to your shapeshifting abilities. In this platformer, you can collect spirit balls by defeating two-headed wolves, allowing you to mutate into different beasts such as a werewolf, a dragon, a tiger, a bear and others depending on the version. Each form, tied to a level, comes with special abilities such as flight and powerful attacks, easily superseding the basic set of punches and kicks in your human form.

The game can be played in singleplayer mode, or in same-screen multiplayer co-op mode.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Altered Beast (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19890814T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Battle Squadron (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Battle Squadron</name>
		<desc>Battle Squadron is a classic arcade style shooter for 1 or 2 players.You take a space ship and fly it over a high tech hostile surface, and then into an organic setting.  

You can control the number of 'credits' you have from 1 to 3.  You choose how many lives you get.  You also get to choose the max number of enemy bullets and their speed.

You get powerups along the way that modify your weapons, and also the "Nova Smart Bomb".</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Battle Squadron (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.55</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Electronic Arts</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Battletoads (World).zip</path>
		<name>Battletoads</name>
		<desc>The Dark Queen has attacked and kidnapped (toadnapped?) your best buddy.. To make matters worse, she nabbed the best looking girl around! So, what will you do? Cry? Whimper? Hide? Call the Starcops? NO! Cause you're a Battletoad! Battletoads don't cry, hide or call for help! And they certainly don't whimper! They get MAD then they get EVEN! So grab your blaster, hop on the Toadster and go get 'em!

You will control a battletoad through various levels. Some are side-scrolling beat-em-ups, other are vertical drops down a shaft, fighting as you go, others have you riding a rocket or surfboard, shooting or avoiding enemies. At the end of each area, there is a boss. In some areas, about half-way through, you may have a mini-boss.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Battletoads (World)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19910713T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Rareware</developer>
		<publisher>Tradewest</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Battletoads-Double Dragon (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Battletoads &amp; Double Dragon</name>
		<desc>Earth is under fire by Colossus, a battleship the size of a city. Using powerful laser cannons, it has destroyed most of Earth's defence forces, while its many troops clean up the rest of the planet. All expect for 5 warriors.

The Battletoads, who are well aware of evil forces in the galaxy, join forces with Billy and Jimmy Lee from Double Dragon to defend Earth from the deadly ship and its troops. Using a range of special moves you must fight your way through the streets into the heart of the ship and destroy it.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Battletoads-Double Dragon (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Rareware</developer>
		<publisher>Tradewest</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse</name>
		<desc>This is the first Mickey Mouse game for Sega consoles. In this game the famous Disney character must face the dangers of weird fantasy lands such as an enchanted forest and a toy world. Mickey must rescue his girlfriend Minnie who's been kidnapped by the evil witch Mizrabel.

The game play follows the traditional 2D hop 'n' bop platform style in both 8-bit and 16-bit versions. Apart from the story and the music, which is the same, all the rest (including controls, moves, stages and, obviously, graphics), are totally different.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform / Run Jump Scrolling</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./DJ Boy (USA).zip</path>
		<name>DJ Boy</name>
		<desc>Skating DJ Boy's girl has been kidnapped by the town's local goons and DJ Boy is the only one who can save the day. This coin-op conversion offers different rounds of side-scrolling beat-em-up gameplay, each with an end boss. DJ Boy is able to punch, kick, combine them in a flying attack and punch to both sides at the same time by pressing the main attack buttons. Although the visuals are less rough and friendlier than its contemporary counterparts, the difficulty is very unforgiving. DJ Boy has only four life bars and when they are gone, the game is over without continues. Defeated enemies leave behind coins. At the end of each stage the coins can be exchanged for a skateboard, a stronger punch or other items.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/DJ Boy (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.55</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Double Dragon (USA, Europe) (Unl).zip</path>
		<name>Double Dragon</name>
		<desc>Set in a post-apocalyptic New York, Double Dragon is the story of Billy and Jimmy Lee, twin brothers trained in the fighting style of Sou-Setsu-Ken. Together, they manage a small martial arts training school, teaching their students in self-defense. One day, Billy's girlfriend, Marian, is kidnapped off the street by the "Black Warriors", a savage street gang led by a man named Willy. The Black Warriors demand the Lee brothers disclose their martial arts secrets in exchange for Marian's freedom. The Lee brothers set out on a rescue mission to crush the Black Warriors and save Marian.

Using whatever techniques they have at their disposal, from the basic punches and kicks to the invulnerable elbow strike, as well any weapon that comes into their hands, the Lee brothers must pursue the gang through the city slum, industrial area and the forest before reaching their hideout to confront the big boss, Willy.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Double Dragon (USA, Europe) (Unl)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19920401T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Tecmo</developer>
		<publisher>Accolade</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Double Dragon 3 - The Arcade Game (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Double Dragon 3 : The Arcade Game</name>
		<desc>The final game in the trilogy.

Billy and Jimmy Lee are returning from martial arts training when their paths cross a fortune teller. She tells them of a great evil in Egypt, their strongest adversary yet, and how the Rosetta Stones can aid them.

This game features weapon shops where Billy and Jimmy can buy power-ups, tricks, energy and extra lives to aid them in 
their quest.

Power-ups make Billy and Jimmy twice their size, increasing their damage done and range of attack.

The character graphics have changed, moving away from cartoon style graphics to more realistic looking characters.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Double Dragon 3 - The Arcade Game (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.2</rating>
		<releasedate>19930201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Flying Edge</developer>
		<publisher>Acclaim</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Double Dragon V - The Shadow Falls (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Double Dragon V : The Shadow Falls</name>
		<desc>Double Dragon returns, this time as a VS. fighter, in the same mold as Street Fighter. Based on the Double Dragon animated series, which is loosely based on the original arcade game, Jimmy and Billy and a host of other characters fight it out in a tournament fighter. 

The Shadow Master, who has created a deadly virus which he plans to destroy the world with, is waiting for you at the end of the path to victory. You'll have to fight your way through many evil characters before you face the Shadow Master. Beat him, and the world is saved for another day.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Double Dragon V - The Shadow Falls (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.2</rating>
		<releasedate>19940805T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Leland Interactive Media</developer>
		<publisher>Tradewest</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Double Dribble - The Playoff Edition (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Double Dribble : The Playoff Edition</name>
		<desc>An updated version of the original Double Dribble basketball game. Double Dribble: The Playoff Edition. The Playoff Edition expands dramatically on the original in a number of ways:

1. 16 teams of 12 (fictitious) players each
2. All players individually rated for various skills (Shooting %, Stamina, etc.)
3. Three play modes: Exhibition, Playoff (with password feature), and Multiplayer
4. 8-way multiplayer support with the Sega "Team Player" adapter
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Double Dribble - The Playoff Edition (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-8</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Earthworm Jim (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Earthworm Jim</name>
		<desc>A crow is chasing a worm named Jim while in outer space Psy-Crow is chasing a renegade ship. The ship's captain has stolen an ultra-high-tech-indestructible-super-space-cyber-suit and Queen Slug-for-a-Butt has ordered Psy-Crow to get it, since it can make her more beautiful than Princess-What's-Her-Name. Psy-Crow blasts the captain and the suit falls to Planet Earth.

Back on earth Jim wonders if he is finally safe when an ultra-high-tech-indestructible-super-space-cyber-suit lands on him. Luckily Jim rests in the neck ring of the suit. Then the space particles begin interacting with Jim, causing a light-speed evolution. Jim soon realizes he is in control of the suit.

Jim overhears the Queen's plans for the suit and decides to meet this Princess...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Earthworm Jim (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19940802T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Shiny Entertainment</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Earthworm Jim 2 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Earthworm Jim 2</name>
		<desc>An ordinary average earthworm named Jim goes about his normal daily life, cruising around avoiding crows and doing other general worm-like things. Jim is suddenly struck by a very large ultra- high- tech- indestructible- super- space- cyber- suit. Through sheer luck, Jim rests safely in the neck ring of the suit. 

Suddenly, the ultra-high-tech space particles of the suit begin interacting with Jim's soft wormy flesh. A radical light-speed evolution takes place.

Jim soon realizes he is in control of the suit.

Gameplay is similar to the first game, with Jim jumping and running through the levels. There are 5 weapons more than the original game to collect. Characters like Princess Whats-Her-Name and Psy-Crow appear.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Earthworm Jim 2 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Playmates Interactive</developer>
		<publisher>Virgin Interactive Entertainment</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Elemental Master (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Elemental Master</name>
		<desc>Elemental Master's gameplay is similar to a top-down space shooter (i.e Raptor &amp; Raiden), but what makes it unique is the fact you play as a human instead of space-ship.

There are different kinds of weapons which you can use. Like other games in the genre you also have tons of strange enemies to destroy.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Elemental Master (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Technosoft</developer>
		<publisher>Renovation Products</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em up / Vertical</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fantasia (World) (Rev A).zip</path>
		<name>Fantasia</name>
		<desc>Fantasia takes place in the dream world of Mickey Mouse as the Sorcerer's Apprentice.

Mickey must find the missing musical notes scattered about in four imaginary worlds.  The Water World, Earth World, Air World and Fire World are filled with magical creatures such as marching brooms, skipping mushrooms, jumping cactus, flying horses, dancing hippos and many more.

The music in the worlds is straight from the movie, including pieces by Bach, Mussorgsky, Beethoven, Tchaikovsky, Stravinsky, Dukas and Ponchielli.

Mickey must collect special items to keep up his strength and earn bonus points. Spell books, stars, crystal balls, potions and dinosaur eggs help him along the way. Enemies are dispatched by bouncing on them or casting small or large spells. If Mickey finds a wooden door he is led to a bonus area where he can collect many magical items.

At the end of each level, Mickey takes the notes he's found back to the orchestra's conductor who will send him back into the world to keep searching if he hasn't found enough of them or gained enough points.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Fantasia (World) (Rev A)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19910801T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>Infogrames</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fatal Fury (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Fatal Fury</name>
		<desc>Southtown City plays host to the King of Fighters Tournament. Andy &amp; Terry Bogard take part in the tournament cause winning the tournament is the only way they can defeat Geese Howard. Geese Howard controls Southtown City and killed their father several years ago. Also taking part is Joe Higashi, a Japanese kickboxer. Select either Joe, Andy or Terry, visit several locations in Southtown City and win that tournament!

Fatal Fury is a 2D fighter and is the first game in a series of one-on-one fighting games by SNK. It's a conversion of the original Fatal Fury arcade game. This first game does not yet feature the series' trademark pseudo 3D mode (which allows you to move between the foreground &amp; background while fighting). Includes a two-player vs. mode.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Fatal Fury (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19930201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>SNK</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Fatal Fury 2 (USA, Korea).zip</path>
		<name>Fatal Fury 2</name>
		<desc>Again, the Lone Wolves return!

Geese Howard may have been defeated, but that doesn't mean all is peaceful. A new opponent, Wolfgang Krauser, has come forth to begin a new Fatal Fury tournament. The Lone Wolves return, with new faces amongst them. Only one can be declared the winner though.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Fatal Fury 2 (USA, Korea)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SNK</developer>
		<publisher>Takara</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Flashback - The Quest for Identity (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Flashback : The Quest for Identity</name>
		<desc>Planet Titan: Brave mutants, robots, anti-matter fields and the primitive inhabitants as you find your way through the jungle. New Washington: First recover your memory, then go undercover to earn money. Finally, buy a false ID if you want to sneak back on Earth. Death Tower: Climb the 8 floors of the Death Tower labyrinth. Avoid the deadly Replicants and win a free ticket to Earth. Earth: Big trouble! The authorities have discovered your false ID and send robot cops to capture you. Paradise Club: You discovered the aliens' plans, but somehow end up being captured and mysteriously transported through space. Planet Morphs: You materialized on their home planet. Now all you have to do is destroy the Morphs and live to tell about it!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Flashback - The Quest for Identity (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.95</rating>
		<releasedate>19930220T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>U.S. Gold</developer>
		<publisher>Delphine Software International</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Forgotten Worlds (World) (v1.1).zip</path>
		<name>Forgotten Worlds</name>
		<desc>Forgotten Worlds features two characters known as The Nameless Ones, who both look like Arnold Schwarzenegger, one even has a mohawk. It's their job to rid the planet of the attacking aliens. 

Guiding your character around the screen as they fly with jet-packs, guns on full auto, you control a satellite which you rotate around your character for the direction in which your gun is firing. At the end of each level is a boss which needs to be killed to progress.

Enemies that have been killed drop money. At the end of every level is a shop where you can buy weapons, armour, items and first-aid packs.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Forgotten Worlds (World) (v1.1)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19900201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Frogger (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Frogger</name>
		<desc>Your task in this arcade conversion is to guide a frog across a treacherous road and river, and to safety at the top of the screen. Both these sections are fraught with a variety of hazards, each of which will kill the frog and cost you a life if contact is made.

The road is full of cars and trucks, at variable speeds. The river water itself is fatal, as are the snakes which hover within on later levels. Frogger must use the arrangement of logs, turtles (which are only there for a short time) and alligators (but stay away form their faces), and then jump into one of the open home-cells, ideally one containing a fly for extra points. Once all holes have been filled, you move onto the next, harder, level.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Frogger (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19980101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Morning Star Multimedia</developer>
		<publisher>Majesco</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gaiares (Japan, USA).zip</path>
		<name>Gaiares</name>
		<desc>It's the year 300x.  The Earth has been ravaged by careless humans, leaving an uninhabitable, polluted wasteland.  The space terrorists, Gulfer, plan to harvest the pollution to make some sort of garbage weapon. The good guys, the Leezaluth, aren't happy about that, so they decide they have to blow up the Earth before Gulfer gets at it.  They give Earth an ultimatum: destroy Gulfer or Leezaluth destroys Earth. To help them out, Leezaluth gives Earth's last hero, Dan, a special weapon: the TOZ system.

Why don't the Leezaluth just stop Gulfer themselves?  It's not exactly clear.

So, we have the premise for a side scrolling shooter. The star attraction here is the TOZ system. The TOZ is an orb that follows your ship around, and can be shot at enemy ships to absorb their weapons. Using the TOZ, Dan will fight through 8 stages filled with lots of enemies and really large bosses.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Gaiares (Japan, USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Telenet</developer>
		<publisher>Renovation Products</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Ghouls'n Ghosts (USA, Europe) (Rev A).zip</path>
		<name>Ghouls'n Ghosts</name>
		<desc>Three years have passed since Arthur defeated the Demon King Astaroth and rescued his beloved Princess Prin-Prin (see Ghosts 'N Goblins). A new villain, the Great Demon King Lucifer (Loki in some versions) has become the new leader of Ghoul Realm. While returning from a journey, Arthur sees the Princess' castle and her village under attack by Lucifer's forces. While rushing towards her beloved knight, the Princess is struck by one of Lucifer's laser beams.

Now, Arthur must venture back to the Lucifer's palace and destroy the demon in order to rescue the Princess' soul and bring her back to life! And it won't matter whether he fights in his shining armor or in his underwear alone...the bravest Knight in the land isn't going to be stopped by some monsters! Although the game starts with graveyard and marsh territory familiar from the first game, later levels are set in a tower, a mass of skeletons, and a castle.

Players progress from left to right (from bottom to top in level 3), and have to hack down the aforementioned monsters with a sword. The journey includes ledges, ladders, lava pits and slippery slopes. Different weapons can be collected, by finding suits of armor inside chests. Each of the five stages has its own setting and a final boss.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Ghouls'n Ghosts (USA, Europe) (Rev A)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19891001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Golden Axe (World) (v1.1).zip</path>
		<name>Golden Axe</name>
		<desc>Sega's classic arcade beat-'em-up game, Golden Axe puts in the shoes of one of three heroes, each with his own reason for trying to overthrow the evil rule of Death-Adder, who - along with his forces of darkness - kidnapped and imprisoned the King and his daughter and stole the legendary Golden Axe.

This is a horizontal fighting game, where you basically take one of the three characters (a warrior, a dwarf or an amazon) and bash everything which stands between you and Death Adder himself.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Golden Axe (World) (v1.1)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19900201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Golden Axe II (World).zip</path>
		<name>Golden Axe II</name>
		<desc>Not long after the malign reign of the Death Adder has ended, another evil rises. The peace of the land has again been threatened, this time by 'Dark Guld', who was supposed to be imprisoned but apparently isn't. He has instead now got his hands on the Golden Axe, and is using it for his own nasty purposes, and with his minions is causing much chaos.

So once more, Ax-Battler, the fierce barbarian; Tyris-Flare, the fearless Amazon; Gilius Thunderhead, the ferocious dwarf; get up to deal with the oppression, with their might and magic, and recover the Golden Axe.

The hack and slash gameplay, in a medieval fantasy setting, is essentially the same to that of the previous game. Beat up opponents with melee attacks and collect scrolls to launch magical attacks. Moreover,  players can also ride dragons and other beasts and use their attack capabilities to their advantage.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Golden Axe II (World)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Gunstar Heroes (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Gunstar Heroes</name>
		<desc>Chaos has broken out on the planet Gunstar-9!!

The mad Colonel Red has discovered four crystals that imprison a deadly being known as GoldenSilver, and plans on unleashing it onto the population of the planet! He must be stopped! Enter...the Gunstar Heroes, Red and Blue!

Unleash some mad blasting action onto the Colonel's army and don't let him bring GoldenSilver to life!! The fate of Gunstar-9 is in your hands!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Gunstar Heroes (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19930909T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Treasure</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shooter</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Joe &amp; Mac (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Joe &amp; Mac</name>
		<desc>The game stars the green-haired Joe and the blue-haired Mac, cavemen who battle though numerous prehistoric levels using, weapons such as boomerangs, bones, fire, flints, electricity, stone wheels, and clubs. The objective of the game is simply rescuing a group of girls who were kidnapped by a rival tribe of cavemen. The gameplay is somewhat similar to Contra and has a Gauntlet-style health system, where the player loses health over a period of time apart from in boss battles. This health system is also not unlike that of Sega's Wonder Boy. The game could be played in either single player or two player mode. In the two player mode, both characters could hurt each other. The game was also notable for its cartoony graphics, humor, and sound effects.

The original arcade version had the distinction of allowing the player to select between different routes (much like Taito's Darius) at the end of a boss battle. Also, after defeating the final boss, the players can choose between three exits, each one leading to a slightly different ending sequence.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Joe &amp; Mac (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Data East</developer>
		<publisher>Takara</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mega Man - The Wily Wars (Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Mega Man : The Wily Wars</name>
		<desc>Mega Man: Wily Wars is a collection of the first three NES Mega Man titles. It features enhanced graphics and sound as well as the game "Wily Tower", a short game that mixes enemies from all three games.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Mega Man - The Wily Wars (Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19941020T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mega Turrican (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Mega Turrican</name>
		<desc>After many generations of peace, the Dark Forces have assembled again, and as a member of the USS Freedom Forces, it is your job to defeat them once again. This means you will have to complete numerous large levels always searching for secrets to pick up and enemies to shoot. To do this, you can pick up three different, upgradeable shots: a multiple, a laser and a rebound. You can also go into wheel-mode (as long as you have enough special energy) or use a rope. In wheel-mode, you are invincible and can lay mines or explore previously unreachable areas.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Mega Turrican (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19940607T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Factor 5</developer>
		<publisher>Data East</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Mickey's Ultimate Challenge (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Mickey's Ultimate Challenge</name>
		<desc>One night, as Mickey (or Minnie) lay in bed reading a book of fairy tales, he started to wonder how it would be to live in a far off land, in a magic castle. As he fell asleep, he woke up in the Kingdom of Beanwick, which is constantly tormented by earthquakes. Then, he offers his help to solve the mystery behind those earthquakes.

Mickey's Ultimate Challenge is a puzzle game in which the player chooses either Mickey or Minnie to play with. They'll find five characters from the Disney's universe in the kingdom, and will be prompted to help them in several tasks.

Each task is a different puzzle, given by a specific character. Daisy, for instance, will ask help to clean the castle's paintings hanging on a wall. The task is in fact a memory game, where Mickey or Minnie must clean the pictures matching pairs. After completing one task, they'll receive a gift.

After completing all tasks, Mickey or Minnie must trade the gifts they won with the right characters. For instance, after finishing Goofy's task, they will receive his hammer. The player must then guess who among the other characters would like to receive that hammer.

Giving the right items to the right characters will allow Mickey or Minnie access to the last puzzle and character.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Mickey's Ultimate Challenge (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19940101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>HiTech Software</developer>
		<publisher>HiTech Software</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./OutRun (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>OutRun</name>
		<desc>Race across varied terrain in this conversion of one of the most famous arcade racing games. Your Ferrari is at the ready, complete with female passenger, over a series of short tracks.

Gameplay is viewed form just above and behind the car, so you can see it. The roads are full of sharp bends and hazards, contact with which can cause the car to roll and lose you time. On each section of track there is a fork in the road, allowing you to choose which direction you go in. You have to complete 5 track sections in total, out of the 15 in the game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/OutRun (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Pocahontas (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Pocahontas</name>
		<desc>Incarnation of the Disney cartoon; Pocahontas, along with a tag team partner in her raccoon friend, Meeko, goes about her homeland, helping her animal friends. As so is done, she will acquire animal spirits which will help her become stronger and bless her with new abilities.

But soon enough she meets John Smith, and as an inevitable consequence has to prevent a war between his and John's people. And she has to do it in a hurry, before John's neck gets a non-&amp;quot;disney&amp;quot; treatment..
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Pocahontas (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19960101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Disney Interactive</developer>
		<publisher>Disney Interactive</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rastan Saga II (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Rastan Saga II</name>
		<desc>The "Rastania" was a sacred place, in which the sacred temple, "Skyscraper", soared into the sky. It is said that whoever conquer the "Skyscraper" would rule the "Rastania". A wicked group has invaded the "Skyscraper" and has tried to make it their own. If the situation is left as it is, the place would eventually be controlled by the wicked group.

Rastan Saga 2 is the sequel to Rastan,   containing the same hack-em'/slash-'em gameplay as the original. You are a warrior who must get through a number of levels, and trying to collect gems which can only be obtained by defeating the end-of-level bosses.  Collecting power-ups along the way awards you with extra life or better weapons.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Rastan Saga II (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.45</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Taito</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Road Rash (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Road Rash</name>
		<desc>Road Rash is an aggressive motorcycle racing game where the player assumes the role of a biker who takes part in a series of illegal races across the U.S.A. Starting at the back of the pack the objective is always to finish first on a linear course, overtaking the other bikers. This is achieved by driving very well or by playing it dirty, knocking opponents of their bikes using clubs, crowbars or your bare hands. The other racers fight back in a similar fashion and there are also hazards. All the races take place on the regular road with normal traffic (in both directions) and the cops, as well as occasional oil slicks and stray cows.

By winning races you can get promoted to a stronger division and earn cash with which you can buy a better bike. Whenever you're knocked off your bike or hit something you will have to run back to your bike and lose valuable time, plus your bike will suffer some damage. When the player crashes with cops nearby, it is possible to get busted and then you have to forfeit the race.

Like the whole Road Rash lineage, the game has arcade-like gameplay with no intention to be a motorcycle simulation. While the game has a two-player mode, this is not simultaneous.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Road Rash (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Electronic Arts</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Road Rash 3 (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Road Rash 3</name>
		<desc>Following the previous two Road Rash games, the player has conquered the US illegal motorcycle championship. But why settle for that when one can take over the World; racing in the peaceful streets of the UK, dodging the animals in Kenya, blaze through the night in Japan or jump in the hilly circuits in Italy?

Keeping the same spirit of the previous two games, Road Rash 3 adds all new digitized sprites (based on the 32-bit remake released an year earlier), bike upgrades, more weapons and meaner police. Most other aspects of the game remain unchanged: the player starts on the lowest division with a small amount of cash and a slow, hard to handle bike. To get more money (and get a faster bike) the player must beat as many of the other 15 racers to the finish line, using all means possible, even kicking and punching them into knockout. By clearing (finishing on the top three spots) all five races on a level, the player advances to the next, where opponents are faster and tougher, the police is more active and a longer race.

As for new gameplay elements in the final title in the series released for Sega's 16-bit console, bikes can also be improved by choosing cheaper upgrades (instead of simply buying new ones) such as tires (less skidding), engine (improves acceleration and top speed), suspension (allows better control while landing after jumps) and body (bike takes more hits before turning into smoking metal). Instead on relying on simple motorbike patrols, the police now has helicopters at their disposal (which try to land on the player) and patrol cars, which attempt to block the path of the bike, forcing it to stop or collide to get a bust. To make things easier (or harder), new weapons were added, some of which allow the carrier to stun an opponent for a few seconds, making him the perfect victim for an incoming vehicle. Also new, if the player finishes the race with a weapon, carries it to the next race.

Each track has it's own features: in the UK, cars drive left on a rainy day, in Australia and Kenya animals wander into the road, in Brazil bikers can get themselves a close-encounter with a car on a crossing, in Italy the hills allow a lot of air-time for light and speedy bikes, Germany, where the icy roads and sharp turns make a deadly combination and finally in Japan the race goes during the night under the neon lights.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Road Rash 3 (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19950301T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Electronic Arts</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Road Rash II (USA, Europe) (v1.2).zip</path>
		<name>Road Rash II</name>
		<desc>A motorcycle racing game with an attitude. You race in varying environments for ever increasing sums of money. With that money you can buy faster and better bikes. There are many objects on the road to watch out for, from cars to rocks to signs, if you hit one you'll go flying and loose valuable time. If you crash too often your bike can get wrecked. You can also attack other racers. The default attack is a punch, but some racers have weapons, which you can steal and use 
against them. The police patrol the various courses, so if you're not careful you can get busted. Road Rash II is not just a racing game but also a fighting game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Road Rash II (USA, Europe) (v1.2)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Electronic Arts</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Race, Driving</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rockman X3 (Taiwan) (En) (Unl).zip</path>
		<name>Rockman X3</name>
		<desc>Rockman X3 is a pirated port of the game of the same name, made for the Mega Drive by an unknown company.  There are two versions of this of this on the internet with slight differences between them, mostly due to stage music.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Rockman X3 (Taiwan) (En) (Unl)-image.png</image>
		<publisher>Homebrew</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rolling Thunder 2 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Rolling Thunder 2</name>
		<desc>A follow up to the original rolling thunder, this game is your basic shot-the-bad-guys-and-save-the-world game.

A terrorist group has taken out the world information flow and, as either a guy named Albert Ross or a woman named Leila, you must stop them. You can also get cool weapons that pack more of a punch than your ordinary hand gun.

Also RT2 is a password supported game, so in other words you get a password at the end of each round so if you loss all your lives, you can continue from the end of that round, very handy.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Rolling Thunder 2 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Rolling Thunder 3 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Rolling Thunder 3</name>
		<desc>The events in the third game in the series are synchronous with RT2. At the end of the twentieth century, satellites around the globe are being shot down, disrupting communications. Secret agency Rolling Thunder discovers the organization behind the terror: Geldra. While agents Leila and Albatross are fighting the leader Gimdo (RT2), agent Jay is instructed to bring down Dread, the second-in-command.

There are many improvements to the gameplay: Jay can shoot while jumping and shoot diagonally upwards with certain weapons. At the beginning of each mission, you can pick a special weapon such as a laser rifle, bazooka, flamethrower or grenades. You have to choose carefully as they cannot be reused in later missions. You can still hide in doorways and recharge your weapons behind special doors. The mission timer from the previous game has been replaced by a sniper that targets you with a crosshair when you don't move fast enough. The brutal difficulty from the previous games has been toned down: there are more life marks at the start and you now resurrect where you died, rather than returning to the last checkpoint. Unlike the previous game, you can only choose one character to play with.

After completing a mission, a password is provided to continue playing. There are ten levels in total, with a few hidden areas.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Rolling Thunder 3 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19930701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Namco</developer>
		<publisher>Namco</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sagaia (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Sagaia</name>
		<desc>Long time ago, the planet of Darius went into ruin but Proco and Tiat of Darius gave birth to a new planet and named it Orga. After the passing of many centuries, Proco Jr. and Tiat Young receive a strange radio broadcast from the galaxy. They discover the radio broadcast is a mayday signal from another descendent of Darius. They board the Silverhawk, preparing to defeat an evil force and journey to the galaxy.

Darius II, or Sagaia as it is known in the West, is the second installment in Taito's premier shoot 'em up series. Its main distinguishing features are the non-linear level system and the enemies, which are different kinds of seafood.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Sagaia (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Taito</developer>
		<publisher>Taito</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shadow Dancer - The Secret of Shinobi (World).zip</path>
		<name>Shadow Dancer : The Secret of Shinobi</name>
		<desc>A.D. 1997, New York City

Having vanquished the evil crime empire, Neo Zeed, the ninja master Shinobi and his combat ninja skills were not heard from for some time. But a new threat arose, in a reptilian form that lived on vicious instinct alone. The colossal monster moved slowly and quietly, and its attack was relentless. The souls unfortunate enough to survive became hostages, and mass panic swept the streets.

It remained only for Shinobi to take action. His weapons were stealth and quickness of attack, his only allies facing overwhelming forces. Relying on Ninja weapons and magic, Shinobi fought on, assisted by his faithful dog.

Shadow Dancer: The Secret of Shinobi is similar to Shadow Dancer for home computers, and consists of five missions containing three stages each. However, there are a few differences between the two. For example, in this Sega Genesis/Mega Drive exclusive, the stages are different, and you rescue hostages rather than disarm bombs.  Each mission ends up with you fighting a boss, and when you defeat each (except the final one), you also participate in a bonus stage where you must shoot all ninja flying towards you.

Some of the enemies are also quite different. Some of the lizards, which appear in later missions,  leave a "lizard coin", which you can collect for bonus lives.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Shadow Dancer - The Secret of Shinobi (World)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shadow of the Beast (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Shadow of the Beast</name>
		<desc>While very young, Aarbron was kidnapped and enslaved by the Priests of the Beast Lord. He grew up on drugs made to destroy his own will and turn him into the Beast Messenger, a powerful creature serving Maletoth, The Beast Lord himself. He did his job, until one day he noticed a man about to be sacrificed in a ritual, his face triggering ancient memories... and as the sacrificial knife descended into the man's body, Aarbron recognizes the face. Of his father.
As his father dies in the altar, memories of his childhood and tormented past at the hands of the Beast Lord emerged, and as feelings of hate over his captors took over him, he swore revenge and fled the temple, knowing the road to avenge his father and redemption would be hard.

Shadow of the Beast, one of Psygnosis most popular titles during the 16-bit computer era is a side-scrolling platformer best known for the use of parallax scrolling along lush graphics, a musical score  by David Whittaker, a iconic cover by Roger Dean and what many consider to be unforgiving gameplay, balancing between the "very challenging" and the "impossible". The player has to navigate through several areas filled with enemies and traps, collecting keys and activating triggers than open new areas or give Aarbron the means to overcome a sub-boss. The number of moves the player has at disposal is limited: duck, jump and only two attacks: punch and a flying kick. While most enemies die with just one hit, the player must time each attack accurately. However, there are also traps of objects that cannot be destroyed, and these require the player to jump, duck or move according the sequence. The player has only one life with 12 hit points that can be replenished by collecting some objects hidden in the level (like an off-route location or a under a megalith), which also contributes to the difficulty level.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Shadow of the Beast (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.65</rating>
		<releasedate>19911101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Reflections Interactive Limited</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shadow of the Beast II (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Shadow of the Beast II</name>
		<desc>Essentially a side-on scrolling beat 'em up in the vain of Way of the Exploding Fist, but with an epic storyline and puzzles a-plenty.

The introduction, now an Amiga classic, shows the Beast-mage stealing your infant sister and the purpose of the game is to rescue her back. On the way a variety of puzzles, sub-quests and really nasty monsters dog your every step.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Shadow of the Beast II (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19921101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Reflections Interactive Limited</developer>
		<publisher>Electronic Arts</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shining Force (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Shining Force</name>
		<desc>In a wondrous land perhaps not so far from our world, a strange and terrible series of events took place. The powers of darkness, led by Dark Dragon, fought for control of the world of Rune. Legendary warriors of light fought them with the ancient and modern weapons of the time, and drove Dark Dragon into another dimension. But Dark Dragon vowed that in 1,000 years, he would be able to break through the inter-dimensional barrier, back into this world. 

A thousand years of peace and tranquility passed. The people of the world were happy to live their lives in contentment, able to spend time rediscovering the magical and technological wonders destroyed by Dark Dragon and using them to benefit all people. 

But the kingdom of Runefaust has begun a massive attack of the kingdoms of Rune - intending to help Dark Dragon return to this world! A small band of warriors has been sent out on a dangerous journey to fight against the dark forces of Runefaust, and you are the leader. Prepare yourself for the ultimate battle! 

Shining Force is a strategy/RPG.  As you make your way through the lands of Rune, you will be joined by other warriors who wish to stop the forces of Runefaust.  Each warrior has their own strengths and weaknesses.  As you progress through the game you will also gain new weapons and spells.  Use them wisely to stop Dark Dragon from arising and causing havoc in Rune.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Shining Force (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Climax Studios</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Strategy</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shining Force II (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Shining Force II</name>
		<desc>Shining Force II is a strategy/RPG hybrid with cartoon-like graphics. The game is comprised of two modes: exploration, in which the hero and his companions engage in the role-playing game standard of talking to townspeople, exploring new lands, and furthering the plot; and battle mode, in which the combat is resolved from a tactical point of view, with individual combats being resolved from a close-up view with animated characters.

The plot consists of such quests as saving a princess from the clutches of demons, rebuilding the hero's hometown, and uniting the various forces of good together against the hero's nemesis. Along the way, the hero will be joined by many characters who seek to aid him in his journey. Several of these characters can only be obtained by completing side quests. In addition, random battles can occur between the programmed scenarios, giving the hero's party a chance to obtain experience and gain levels outside of the set scenarios.

There are several difficulty levels in the game, selectable when starting a new game. In addition, there is a configuration code that allows cheats to be activated, including the ability to control the enemy units.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Shining Force II (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19941002T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Camelot Software</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Role playing games</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Shinobi III - Return of the Ninja Master (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Shinobi III : Return of the Ninja Master</name>
		<desc>Shinobi III involves a ninja named Joe "Shinobi" Musashi (you) going and kicking some bad guy butt, in this case his old enemy "Neo Zeed".

In normal Shinobi style, you are presented with side-scrolling playfields which you must slash and shuriken your way through, to meet the end boss of each round.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Shinobi III - Return of the Ninja Master (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19930822T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Megasoft</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic The Hedgehog (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Sonic The Hedgehog</name>
		<desc>Sonic the Hedgehog is the first of many games starring Sega's premier rodent Sonic. It's a side scrolling platform game with a difference: speed. Sonic rushes through levels with incredible speed, allowing him to traverse loops and jumps with ease. The evil Dr. Robotnik has captured many of Sonic's animal friends and trapped them inside robots. Sonic can free his friends by destroying the robots with his spin attack. Meanwhile, Dr. Robotnik is trying to control the all-powerful chaos emeralds and Sonic must grab them before he does in the 3D rotating bonus levels. Sonic's weapon is his spin attack; while jumping, Sonic destroys hostile robots by touch. Throughout the platforming levels Sonic collects numerous rings. If Sonic is hit by an enemy, all the rings he's carrying fall out and scatter around; Sonic can quickly grab the rings back before they disappear. If Sonic is hit while not carrying any rings, he dies. Collecting 100 rings gives Sonic an extra life. There is also an invincibility bonus which temporarily protects Sonic from all attacks. The game is divided into several "zones", each of them containing three levels. At the end of each zone Sonic confronts Dr. Robotnik in a boss fight. Sonic the Hedgehog is a significant game because it gave Sega it's first real mascot, and established the Genesis as the video game system with "attitude."</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Sonic The Hedgehog (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19910623T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic The Hedgehog 2 (World) (Rev A).zip</path>
		<name>Sonic The Hedgehog 2</name>
		<desc>Sonic the Hedgehog 2 is a side-scrolling platformer based around speed, and the sequel to Sonic the Hedgehog. Players run through different worlds called "Zones", each with a specific theme. There are two Acts in nearly all of the 10 Zones, and at the end of each Zone's last Act is a machine that Robotnik controls, which you must defeat to progress. Sonic and Tails can collect rings which are scattered throughout all of the levels. When the player collects 100 rings they earn an extra life. The rings also act as protection - if Sonic is hurt when he is carrying rings, they scatter everywhere and he is briefly invincible. If he is hit again when he has no rings, he'll lose a life. If the player reaches a continue point lamppost with 50 or more rings, they'll be able to access the Special Stage. In this stage, you must gather a set amount of rings in a halfpipe-like stage before you reach a checkpoint. Complete all the checkpoints and you'll earn one of the seven Chaos Emeralds. The game also includes the ability to play the game co-op with a friend - at any time, a player can plug in a second controller and take over the AI controlled Tails. Tails has infinite lives and the camera remains focused on Sonic, meaning that Tails will not hinder play. Sonic (and Tails) can now also get speed from a standing start by holding down and repeatedly pressing the jump button for a "Spin Dash". This is useful when stuck near steep slopes or other areas where you need some momentum. The game also features a 2-player versus mode. This mode is a horizontally split-screen race through levels based on three of the zones in the single player game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Sonic The Hedgehog 2 (World) (Rev A)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19921124T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sonic The Hedgehog 3 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Sonic The Hedgehog 3</name>
		<desc>Sonic the Hedgehog 3 is the third in the Sonic series of games. As with the previous games, it is a side-scrolling platformer based around speed. The basic game remains the same - players collect rings to earn extra lives, which are also used for protection, and scatter everywhere when Sonic is hurt. Sonic can jump on enemies to defeat them, and Spin Dash by holding down and the jump button, then letting go of down. Dr. Robotnik's Death Egg has crash-landed on Floating Island, so called because it harnesses the power of the Chaos Emeralds to float in the air. Robotnik needs them to repair the Death Egg, so he tells the guardian of Floating Island, Knuckles the Echidna, that Sonic and Tails are there to steal them. With Knuckles tricked and trying to stop the heroes at every turn, will they be able to stop Robotnik in time? New to Sonic 3 are three different types of shields; the Fire Shield (which protects you from fire but disappears if you enter water), the Water Shield (which lets you breathe underwater infinitely), and the Electric Shield (which pulls nearby rings towards you). </desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Sonic The Hedgehog 3 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19940123T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Sonic Team</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Street Fighter II - Champion Edition.zip</path>
		<name>Street Fighter II' : Special Champion Edition</name>
		<desc>From the corners of the globe come twelve of the toughest fighters to ever prowl the streets. Choose your champion and step into the arena as one of the eight original challengers or as one of the four Grand Masters! Pound your opponent as Balrog and knock them out for the count. Tower over your prey as Sagat and daze them with your awesome Tiger Shot. Slash your opponent with Vega's claw and send them running for cover. Or strike fear into your enemies as M. Bison, the greatest Grand Master of them all!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Street Fighter II - Champion Edition-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Street Fighter II' - Special Champion Edition (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Street Fighter II' : Special Champion Edition</name>
		<desc>From the corners of the globe come twelve of the toughest fighters to ever prowl the streets. Choose your champion and step into the arena as one of the eight original challengers or as one of the four Grand Masters! Pound your opponent as Balrog and knock them out for the count. Tower over your prey as Sagat and daze them with your awesome Tiger Shot. Slash your opponent with Vega's claw and send them running for cover. Or strike fear into your enemies as M. Bison, the greatest Grand Master of them all!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Street Fighter II' - Special Champion Edition (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Streets of Rage (World).zip</path>
		<name>Streets of Rage</name>
		<desc>Streets of Rage, Sega's answer to Final Fight, follows the story of three young police officers (Adam Hunter, Axel Stone and Blaze Fielding) in a city controlled by a criminal syndicate led by a "Mr. X" where crime is rampant, which leads the three heroes to make a pact to leave the force and topple the syndicate by themselves.

Gameplay is straightforward and simple. Three buttons are used, one to jump, other to attack and another to perform a range attack from a support police car. Each character has a limited set of moves that include punching and kicking or performing a back attack (if in the open), two grapple moves (depending if holding the opponent in front or by the back), a flying attack, and if playing with another player two additional tag attacks, and different abilities: Adam is slow, but a good jumper and a hard hitter, Axel fast and also a hard hitter, but a lousy jumper and Blaze fast and a good jumper, but weak hitter.
Levels are in typical arcade side-scroller fashion: move from left to right (with two exceptions), clearing screens from enemies one after another as fast as possible while avoid taking damage with a boss in the end. Some levels feature "death drops" where the player must avoid falling, while throwing enemies there at the same time, including a typical elevator level.  Several items are scattered on the ground, from melee weapons and bonus points (and lives or additional police cars) to apples and turkeys (to restore health).</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Streets of Rage (World)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19910701T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Streets of Rage 2 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Streets of Rage 2</name>
		<desc>After Axel Stone, Blaze Fielding and Adam Hunter destroyed the evil Syndicate leader, Mr. X, the city became a peaceful place to live, and each one of them followed their own paths. One year later, after their reunion, Adam's brother Sammy returned from school to find their apartment in a mess, and Adam nowhere to be seen, and after calling his two friends, one of them notices a photo of Adam chained to a wall, next to someone they knew very well - Mr. X, who returned to turn the peaceful city once again into a war zone. Now, Axel, Blaze, Sammy, and Axel's good friend Max, a pro wrestler, must head out to stop Mr. X once again...hopefully for good...

Streets of Rage 2 differs from the previous title in several ways. There are changes in both graphics (characters now are bigger, more detailed and with more animation frames, and scenarios are less grainy) and gameplay (the rocket move was replaced by a special move that doubles in offense and defense along several new moves), along other new features such as life bars (and names) for all enemies and the radically different new characters.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Streets of Rage 2 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19921201T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Streets of Rage 3 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Streets of Rage 3</name>
		<desc>Streets of Rage 3 aimed to build on the success of its predecessor, so while the style of gameplay and control scheme is largely identical to its predecessors, significant changes were made to the overall structure of the game. Streets of Rage 3 is a faster paced release with longer levels, a more complex plot (which in turn leads to more in-depth scenarios complete with interactive levels and multiple endings) and the return of traps such as pits. Dash and dodge moves were added to each character's arsenal of moves, and weapons can now only be used for a few times before breaking.

Changes to the fighting mechanics allows for the integration of weapons with certain movesets. Team attacks, absent from Streets of Rage 2 but available in the original Streets of Rage, make a return, and are occasionally used by enemies too. Blitz moves, performed while running, have also been altered and are now upgradable over the course of the game (predicated on how many points are earned per level). Death causes a downgrade, however holding the X button before a series of button combinations can give players access to the upgraded moveset at any point in the game, at the expense of the time taken to perform attacks.

Enemies are also smarter with weapons, and some can even steal health upgrades, and there are also several secret playable characters, unlockable after overcoming certain conditions during the game. Special moves also no longer drain the user's health - a separate, automatically regenerating bar is introduced for this purpose.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Streets of Rage 3 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19970317T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Strider (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Strider</name>
		<desc>The year is 2089AD. In Russia, the evil Grand Master Meio has begun his insane plot to take over the universe. A lone figure drops from a stealth glider into Meio's base. He is Hiryu, Super A-Class Strider. His mission is to defeat the Grand Master and put an end to his plotting once and for all.

Converted from the classic arcade game, Strider lets you run, jump, perform acrobatics and climb walls and overhangs. You wield a plasma sword, called a Cypher, through 5 levels fighting robots and guards, with mid- and end-level bosses.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Strider (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19901101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Strider Returns - Journey from Darkness (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Strider Returns : Journey from Darkness</name>
		<desc>Strider has been called into action to save the people of the planet Magenta, armed with a Gyro laser and matter converter. He must fight his way through a forest, a ruined city, underground colonies, a roof-top battle, and finally the prison ship in which the Megantan leader is held.

The gameplay is similar to the original, consisting of running, jumping and attacking, with a very dynamic central character. The laser gun can be used while standing still; moving attacks with the sword are still possible, with the two weapons combining similarly to the Switchblade games. Tokens can be collected, which will turn you into a robot to face the end-of-level enemies if enough are collected.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Strider Returns - Journey from Darkness (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19930101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Tiertex</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Striker (Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Striker</name>
		<desc>The first game in the long-running soccer series, which stood out from the crowd with a unique forced perspective 3D view rather than a simple overhead one. The players are drawn large and there is a large scanner to assist with long passing. However, the standard mode has the ball sticking closely to the feet, which makes mazy runs upfield a more useful strategy. There are 64 international teams on offer, with a European-style knock-out cup competition included. Many different formations and strategies are offered.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Striker (Europe)-image.png</image>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Sports / Soccer</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Sub-Terrania (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Sub-Terrania</name>
		<desc>Aliens have invaded a vital subterranean mining colony. Use light-speed reflexes and total concentration to fly your prototype fighter through impossible caverns rescuing miners and blast those aliens into the darkest pits of space!

The game consists of 10 missions. Each mission takes place in a vast cavern, with interesting weather conditions. You must explore it and complete the mission objectives -- usually collecting sub parts, rescuing trapped miners, or destroying giant, epic bosses. You can also explore the levels, but keep an eye on your fuel gauge and beware the many hazards!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Sub-Terrania (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19940301T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Zyrinx</developer>
		<publisher>Scavenger</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Super Mario Bros. (Taiwan) (En) (Unl).zip</path>
		<name>Super Mario Bros.</name>
		<desc>Super Mario Bros. is a unauthorized port of game (with the same name) to Mega Drive. It was released as homebrew for the console as SMB4MD. However, as many MD homebrew games, it was sold as a pirate game and it was credited to KDS (Kudos), and most of the times, was bundled with BattleCity (which was also a homebrew port), and also is credited by KDS.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Super Mario Bros. (Taiwan) (En) (Unl)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<publisher>Gamtec</publisher>
		<genre />
		<players />
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Syd of Valis (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Syd of Valis</name>
		<desc>SYD of Valis is a reworked version of the action-platformer Valis II with simplified gameplay and a "Super Deformed" and kid-friendlier graphic design.

In the game you play as Yuko (Syd in the localized version), a teenage schoolgirl that can wield the magical sword of Valis and must travel to the dreamworld of Vekanti to defeat the evil lurking within it.

The game plays as a side-scrolling action platformer, in which you avoid obstacles by running and jumping around, and must defeat enemies by striking them with your blade. You can collect power-ups that include different weapons and armor types, all of which you can equip at any time during the game.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Syd of Valis (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.5</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Renovation Products</developer>
		<publisher>Laser Soft</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - The Legend Returns (Russia) (Unl).zip</path>
		<name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - The Legend Returns</name>
		<desc>We all love those shelled-up Pizza addicts... as do the Russians apparently. An all new and somewhat original Mega Drive title starring the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles has been in circulation recently, flooding the Russian after-market of 16-bit software. Luckily for gamers elsewhere around the world, the game's ROM file has been preserved and since shared online.

As excited as we were reading about another 16-bit adventure for our anthropomorphic turtles, the reality of what we have here is somewhat disappointing, although interesting. Similar to the many other Russian releases on the Sega Mega Drive, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: The Legend Returns takes elements from other titles without permission - this time from Ubisoft's flash game to promote Smash Up, Double Damage.

Making use of the assets taken from other sources, the Russians have created their very own Street of Rage clone (or should we say Hyperstone Heist clone), albeit a lacklustre attempt. Gameplay, the repeating scenery and poor enemy AI aside, during our initial play-through we encountered an unbeatable Mouser who began walking in a bizarre fashion, blocking any further progress.

Regardless of how well this title handles and whether or not level two can be beaten, Mega Drive fans should check out this unofficial offering, whilst looking towards the many other original titles Russia has produced for the 16-bit system over the years.</desc>
		<releasedate>19931203T000000</releasedate>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - The Hyperstone Heist (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles : The Hyperstone Heist</name>
		<desc>The Turtles' nemesis Shredder has acquired the HyperStone from Dimension X, and is using its powers to shrink down the city buildings. He threatens to take over the world and challenges the Turtles to deny him, and so the turtles head out to beat the guy once more.

A standard Ninja Turtles beat-em-up action game.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - The Hyperstone Heist (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Beat'em Up</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - Tournament Fighters (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles : Tournament Fighters</name>
		<desc>The game features the original 4 turtles from the previous games in the series, as well as other fighters.

The game is very much in the tradition of the Mortal Kombat or Street Fighter series, pitting you against opponents one at a time. Some fighters (besides the turtles) will be familiar, such as the Rat King, or even Shredder (now called "Cyber-Shredder" here).

Though even people familiar with the turtles will see differences in them. They can now, for example, do moves involving projectiles, such as "fireballs".

The game's modes include a story mode, where you can only pick one of the turtles and go on fighting opponents in order to rescue April and Splinter, and a tournament mode, where you fight only for the fame and money.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles - Tournament Fighters (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.55</rating>
		<releasedate>19931202T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Fight</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Great Circus Mystery Starring Mickey &amp; Minnie, The (USA).zip</path>
		<name>The Great Circus Mystery Starring Mickey &amp; Minnie</name>
		<desc>Starring Mickey and Minnie Mouse, the two plan to spend the day at the Circus only to find that it's deserted. Believing that someone is responsible, you must dress up in different outfits such as Safari and Western, as you try to find clues to solve the mystery behind the disappereance of the performers, including your pals Donald Duck and Pluto.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Great Circus Mystery Starring Mickey &amp; Minnie, The (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19950101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Capcom</developer>
		<publisher>Capcom</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Revenge of Shinobi, The (USA, Europe) (Rev B).zip</path>
		<name>The Revenge of Shinobi</name>
		<desc>You are Musashi, master ninja. You are a mystic warrior, who sees and know all things. You are deadly! Now you must destroy the vicious army of Neo Zeed, or Naoko, their beautiful prisoner, dies!
Attack with a ninja sword and shurikens! Somersault over fences while hurling deadly knives! Ward off bullets, death stars and junked cars by leaping, twisting and kicking!
Stalk ninjas, musclemen, Kung Fu gangs and armies of machine gunners through 24 treacherous scenes. The Neo Zeed are masters of disguise. But you are Shinobi, a master in the art of stealth. And you have a secret weapon - ninja magic!</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Revenge of Shinobi, The (USA, Europe) (Rev B)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Turrican (USA, Europe) (Unl).zip</path>
		<name>Turrican</name>
		<desc>Three-headed demon Morgul has been influencing people's dreams to create nightmares, but more recently these nightmares have become real. Only Turrican can save them in this fast paced side scrolling shoot-em up. It features 5 worlds and 13 levels of challenging gameplay.

Gameplay is conceptually simple: just jump, shoot and explore. However, this game puts a lot of emphasis on finding and using the 10 different weapons Turrican can collect.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Turrican (USA, Europe) (Unl)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>The Code Monkeys</developer>
		<publisher>Accolade</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Twin Cobra - Desert Attack Helicopter (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Twin Cobra : Desert Attack Helicopter</name>
		<desc>Conversion of the Toaplan original game, this conversion is based on the Japanese 1 player version (Ultimate Tiger).

You pilot the TC-17 Twin Cobra assault helicopter to fight the forces of Commander Anziga, the myopic leader of the nation of Kaban. Your job is to fly into Kaban and take out the entire military base of Commander Anziga.

You will fight small helicopters, tanks and stationary guns, defeat the large helicopters to get power-ups. By picking up colored icons (blue, yellow, red or green) you can change to different weapon types. Blue is a forward spread shot, yellow is a four-way shot, red is a wide forward laser shot and green is a continuous forward laser shot.

At the end of each section, you land on a carrier ship and count up your bonuses.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Twin Cobra - Desert Attack Helicopter (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.7</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Toaplan</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Valis (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Valis</name>
		<desc>Yuko Asou is an ordinary Japanese teenager with an ordinary life - until one day she is attacked by a monster on the street. Out of nowhere, a sword appears in her hands. She fights the monsters who have suddenly invaded the city, and is summoned to the parallel world known as Vecanti, which is ruled by a cruel tyrant named Rogles, whose actions disrupt the balance of the the worlds. Wielding the legendary Valis sword, Yuko must defeat Rogles and restore the balance.

Valis has the same story and basic genre (platform action) as the  original first game in the  series; however, it is a different game with different locations, regular enemies and bosses, new cut scenes, etc.  Defeating the numerous enemies populating the game world requires precise usage of jumping and ducking abilities, and attack timing. Yuko can jump very high and attack while jumping. Various power-ups are scattered through the game, many of which enhance the performance of Yuko's sword. Acting as a melee weapon in the beginning, it can be customized with power-ups and turn into a medium-range weapon, firing shots at the enemies - with proper power-ups, also in different directions. Boss enemies typically have different attack patterns and require different strategies to defeat them.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Valis (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Riot</developer>
		<publisher>Renovation Products</publisher>
		<genre>Role playing games</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Valis III (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Valis III</name>
		<desc>Somewhere in the Dark World, evil rears its ugly head once again...

A black-hearted man named Glames, possessor of a sword named Leethus, threatens the Human World, the Dream World, and the Dark World with complete and utter destruction. A young girl from the Dark World named Cham escapes from Glames, and seeks help to destroy him.

She comes to the Human World, searching for the Valis Warrior, Yuko Ahso, and more importantly, the Valis Sword.

Yuko must now help Cham defeat Glames before the three worlds are torn apart!

New improvements over the previous two Valis games include 3 playable characters, 3 unique weapons for each character, and greater, more powerful magic spells.
</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Valis III (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Telenet</developer>
		<publisher>Telenet</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Vectorman (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Vectorman</name>
		<desc>In 2049, the human population of Earth embarks on a migratory voyage to try to colonize other planets. They leave mechanical "orbots" to clean up the mess they made on Earth through littering and pollution. Raster, a high-level orbot who watches Earth through a planetwide computer network, is accidentally attached to a working nuclear missile by a lesser orbot and goes insane, becoming an evil dictator named Warhead. He declares himself ruler of Earth, and begins preparing to execute any humans who dare return to their planet.

Enter Vectorman, a humble robot in charge of cleaning up toxic sludge by simply discharging it into the sun. As he lands on Earth after his last trip, he finds chaos and confusion. Because all the other Orbots are controlled by Warhead (Vectorman having not been affected because he was away), Vectorman takes it upon himself to destroy the errant orbot and restore peace to Earth.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Vectorman (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19951024T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>BlueSky Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Vectorman 2 (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Vectorman 2</name>
		<desc>This is a sequel to  Vectorman. This time, the super-powerful little robot was attacked while coming back to earth in his spaceship. He falls down on the earth only to discover dark locations full of hostile creatures and to participate in a platformer full of fast and furious action. Fight your enemies, collect photons, jump over obstacles, find weapons, morph into other creatures, and climb walls as the green "orbot" Vectorman.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Vectorman 2 (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19961115T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>BlueSky Software, Inc.</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./World of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck (USA, Korea).zip</path>
		<name>World of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck</name>
		<desc>World of Illusion is sort of a follow-up to Castle of Illusion. Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck are taken to a magic world and have to get back home. In order to do that, they can play magical tricks and interact to each other in a 2-player mode. Like other Disney games for SEGA consoles of the same period, the game has cartoon-like graphics and is played as a side-scrolling platformer.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/World of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse and Donald Duck (USA, Korea)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.75</rating>
		<releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>SEGA</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<players>1-2</players>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Zero Wing (Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Zero Wing</name>
		<desc>Zero Wing is an horizontal shooter game where the player is in control of a ZIG, an escape pod released after its main ship was attacked and destroyed by the evil cyborg CATS, bent on taking over the world.

Like most games in the genre, there are three color-coded weapons: red (scatter), green (homing) and blue (lasers). Each weapon has three levels of power, and to obtain those, similar upgrades must be collected sequentially. However, what makes the game unique is the ability to use a traction beam to trap an enemy and then throw him against his peers, destroying them.

The game (or the European PAL version) is best known for being the origin of the infamous "All Your Base" 2001 Internet meme.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Zero Wing (Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.6</rating>
		<releasedate>19910531T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Toaplan</developer>
		<publisher>Toaplan</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em up / Horizontal</genre>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Castlevania - Bloodlines (USA).zip</path>
		<name>Castlevania : Bloodlines</name>
		<desc>In the year 1917, evil had threatened to rise up again in Transylvania. A young lady named Elizabeth Bartley, who was tried as a witch and killed centuries before, was planning to resurrect the Prince of Darkness, Count Dracula, once again.

The latest of the Belmont lineage, John Morris, and his friend Eric Lecarde, must now travel across Europe to the Palace of Versailles in France, where Bartley is planning the resurrection. And in their way stands Dracula's strongest followers yet...</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Castlevania - Bloodlines (USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.9</rating>
		<releasedate>19940317T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Konami</developer>
		<publisher>Konami</publisher>
		<genre>Platform</genre>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
		<playcount>1</playcount>
		<lastplayed>20220721T001934</lastplayed>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Thunder Force II (USA, Europe).zip</path>
		<name>Thunder Force II</name>
		<desc>Thunder Force II is both a side scrolling and top down shooter. In the game you control a ship. In some stages the action is side scrolling and in others it is top down (overhead). The weapons systems is fairly basic. You can switch from shooting a more powerful weapon straight ahead or two less powerful guns shooting forward and backward simultaneously. There are various power-ups that improve your fire power. 

In the top down levels you can only travel in cardinal directions and cannot maneuver around obstacles easily or slow down. The control in the side scrolling levels is reminiscent of R-Type or Gradius, but with more basic weapons systems. In future incarnations of the series the top down aspect would be abandoned.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Thunder Force II (USA, Europe)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.8</rating>
		<releasedate>19890814T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Technosoft</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
	</game>
	<game>
		<path>./Thunder Force III (Japan, USA).zip</path>
		<name>Thunder Force III</name>
		<desc>The famous shoot'em up series Thunder Force reaches its third installment. Eight new levels of non-stop action, as always packed with gargantuan bosses. 

What made Thunder Force stand apart from the other shooters, the ability to switch weapons on the fly, hasn't changed a bit.
However, the original mix of side-scrolling and top-view levels that was present in Thunder Force II has been dropped; only the side-scrolling levels remain.</desc>
		<image>~/.emulationstation/downloaded_images/megadrive/Thunder Force III (Japan, USA)-image.png</image>
		<rating>0.85</rating>
		<releasedate>19901001T000000</releasedate>
		<developer>Technosoft</developer>
		<publisher>SEGA</publisher>
		<genre>Action</genre>
		<favorite>true</favorite>
	</game>
</gameList>
